Matthew Incardona

UX Engineer, Entrepeneur

Passionate entrepreneur with over 5 years of experience as a freelance web designer, bringing together design and development knowledge to help businesses build user-centered experiences. Personable and skilled in project planning and team management. Currently looking for a co-op for Summer 2024.

Experience

Co-Founder, UX Engineer

Second Desk LLC - Stony Brook, NY

March 2021 - Present

- Creating a business-facing desktop-as-a-service product in an Agile, multidisciplinary team.
- Designing high-fidelity prototypes for UI solutions using Figma and presenting them for team feedback.
- Creating a cross-platform, WebRTC-enabled remote desktop app that can be connected to from only a browser.

AWS - React - Electron - NodeJS

Web Designer

DouxDolci Web Design - Stony Brook, NY

July 2018 - Present

- Working directly with a variety of clients to design, build, and host custom WordPress websites on an in-house sever solution.
- Balancing client expectations with their available budget and projected timeline to ensure the project fits their needs.

WordPress - Figma - Illustrator - Photoshop - Oracle Cloud

Agile Process Intern

Peraton - Reston, VA

June 2023 - August 2023

- Engaged with key stakeholders across various departments to understand their unique needs and concerns. This involved conducting in-depth interviews, workshops, and surveys to gather insights.
- Based on the insights gained, we created detailed mockups and prototypes of the proposed tool. These visual representations allowed stakeholders and end-users to visualize the changes and provide early feedback.

Information Architecture - UX Research - UI Design - Figma

UI/UX Dev Researcher

Open@RIT - Rochester, NY January 2023 - May 2023

- Created websites for a variety of open source projects using Jekyll and Tailwind, then deployed them using GitHub pages.
- Redesigned websites using Figma by following a consistent brand style guide and modern design practices.
- Worked with professors to develop their grant project by creating user personas, user journeys, and suggestions on implementation.

GitHub - Tailwind - Jekyll - UX Research

Education

BS in Human-Centered Computing

Class of 2024

Rochester Institute of Technology, 3.7 GPA

Rochester, NY

Links

matthewincardona.com linkedin.com/in/matthew-incardona

Email

Cell

mpi7253@rit.edu

631-371-7358